WWW.MY-SUBS.COM
I want you to be alive after your
entire family is dead
that is what will hurt you the most.
Michael is badly wounded.
John is dead.
So I sent a message to Aberama Gold.
I need you back. I'll help you
cos Michael wants me to help
you. Starting now.
The bullet's been written.
He, as the oldest brother...
I'll put this bullet into his head.
You said you'd bring every man
and woman out on strike.
Do you have a whistle?
It's almost as if you want trouble.
All right. First come, first served,
form an orderly line, all of you.
All right. All right.
Right! Have your contracts of
employment in your hand!
Bring 'em in! Get in there.
Get moving! On you go!
Go on, keep going!
Keep going. Whoa, where
are you going? Bradley. Foreman.</fon
All right. You go
and see that man over there. Go!
What's your name?
Bradley. I'm a foreman.
When did you last work here? 1922.
How many have done this
type of work before?
They're mostly farm hands from down
Worcester way. But I'll show 'em.
Hungry men learn fast.
All right. On you go.
Dirty scabs! Blacklegs!
What bastard threw that?
Get him out here!
Arthur! Oi! Enough. Get him out!
Get out!
Ten more!
Two more. Ten. That's it.
Clo
Right. Ten bob a man.
£2 there for you.
What about security?
Yeah, well, about that...
By order of the city of Birmingham
police department,
you and your ugly workforce
are now under the protection...
..of the Peaky fucking Blinders.
Mr Gray? Yeah, send him in.
It's your mother.
Oh, fuck.
I read about it in the paper.
I have a right.
I'm your mum, as well.
You want me to go away?
Yes.
I'll just leave these.
They're from our orchard.
You used to love these.
I hope there are no worms in them.
Look, I just wanted to say that
you're welcome to come home.
To get better at home.
I know you got
bored in the village, but...
..we love you -
and your little brother misses
playing football with you...
..and your dad...
..passed on.
He passed on
peacefully in our bed.
Fuck.
Now go on.
I'm expecting Tommy,
and he's due here now.
I'll go, then.
I'll not be in the same
room as that man.
Come on, Pol, Tommy's expecting us.
Who's with us?
Isaiah and two Lee boys.
Ada, how long
since you've had a fuck?
What?
It's been nearly two years with me.
Over Christmas I counted it up.
So, I've made a New Year's
resolution to change the situation.
Oh. Anyone particular in mind?
Not really.
Just me and someone unsuitable.
♪ From starry eyes colliding
♪ From Mars to someone crying... ♪
I'll sit in the front.
♪ I'm never far away
♪ No matter what I'm hiding
♪ I get lost
♪ But I always come around
♪ Call when you're ready
cos I'm ready to ride. ♪
So, this is just
to make things official.
Your official return
to the company payroll.
So no more talk
of New Year's resolutions
or Tommy might change his mind.
What New Year's resolution?
Never mind.
I think Ada's trying to tell me
to behave myself.
Yeah. Behave yourself.
Behave myself or what?
Behave myself or fucking what?
OK, Polly, I'll tell you the truth.
After your recent troubles, Tommy
asked me to keep an eye on you.
"Troubles?"
Whilst working for this company,
I have killed a man,
I have lost a man,
I have found a son,
I have nearly lost a son,
I have nearly lost my own life.
Now, I will accept my job back,
if the terms on offer
are favourable...
..but I will not behave myself.
Sorry I'm late.
Where's Arthur?
Do I look like his fucking mother?
Oh, no. Why are you here?
You all right? Is Billy all right?
Yes. Everything's fine.
Well, look... Lovely to see you,
but I'm late for a meeting.
They can wait.
I've got something for you.
Something for a loving husband
who's been working very hard...
..and is under a great
deal of pressure.
Something to relieve his stress.
It's silk. From Japan.
Feel.
My hands are dirty.
Good.
Feel all of it.
Feel it properly.
You, er... You want to do this here?
Why not? I thought
you were the boss.
I am the fucking boss.
Then tell me what to do, boss.
Come here.
Right, before we start this
extraordinary general meeting
of the board of the Shelby
Company Limited,
I'd like to note the absence
of the Deputy Vice President,
who has not yet arrived.
We'll continue without his presence.
Item number one.
The reinstatement of the Shelby
Company Limited company treasurer.
The board welcomes back
the former treasurer,
with generously improved
terms and conditions.
Due to the exceptionally
difficult circumstances
the company now finds itself in.
The proposed treasurer will now
check the terms and conditions,
to see if they are in order.
Item number two, during the absence
of the Company Accountant,
due to ill health,
all responsibility for the keeping
of the Company Accounts
pass to the head of acquisitions.
Item number three.
The Company Treasurer,
having read the terms and condition,
lodges a signed contract
of employment agreeing
to the terms and conditions
with the temporary head of accounts.
All those in favour of the
reinstatement of Mrs Elizabeth Gray
to the position of The Shelby
Company treasurer,
please raise your hands.
Why, goodness. Thank you.
Any other business?
Right, I declare this extraordinary
general meeting over.
Now we talk about
the real business...
..but, for that, we need Arthur.
Where the fuck is Arthur?
Mr Shelby! Fuck off.
They've broken into the paint shop.
Oh, yeah?
They're chucking paint around -
I think they mean
to set light to it.
Well, you deal with it, man,
I'm fucking busy!
What was all that about?
In this sinful place,
there will be temptations.
It's my responsibility as your wife
to help you resist
those temptations.
By putting myself between you...
..and the devil.
In the words of my sinful
Catholic mother,
"Keep his balls empty
and his belly full."
God rest her soul.
Mr Shelby!
You have to come to the
paint shop immediately! Please!
Oh, I have to go.
Won't be late.
Sorry, ladies,
there's no smoking in here.
Yes, love, we know.
All right. He's an hour late.
Fuck him.
This business directly affects
Arthur, but he's not here,
so we'll take a vote without him.
What business?
Official business that wasn't
on your agenda, Ada.
An informant told us
that six years ago Luca Changretta
came from New York to Birmingham to
be best man at his cousin's wedding.
We found out that they used
Reid and Dunn in Broadgate
for the photographs.
The photographer kept the negatives.
I persuaded him to give us copies...
..and to enlarge this one.
That is Luca Changretta.
I've seen his face,
so I could pick him out.
Half the men in the photograph
are Changrettas,
which means the chances are
they're the men will come kill us.
We need to get both these
photographs
into pubs and on street corners,
and put it about that there's
a reward for information.
We also propose that we give
a copy of this photograph
to Mr Aberama Gold.
We need to forget the idea that it
has to be Arthur
that pulls the trigger.
Tradition will just fuck us up.
We should wait for Arthur.
Arthur's not here, Ada.
We need Luca Changretta dead.
That's it.
Dropping the law of the bullet is
part of the process of modernisation
that I was working on
before I were...
..before I was executed.
You weren't executed, Pol.
What did you call me?
Right. Let's take a vote.
I'll deal with Arthur.
All those in favour of giving
the photographs
to Mr Gold raise your hand.
Then it will be done.
Mum... Oh, "mum" now, is it?
I smelt perfume when I came in here.
Yeah, it was the flowers.
Right, that's it.
Who came in here, Michael?
The truth is, Polly, the woman
that raised him came in here.
She has every right to come in here.
She brought him fucking apples
and she left.
We're in the middle of a vendetta
and Arthur's missing.
We need to find him.
Concentrate on what unites us.
This is all temporary.
Yeah, temporary, right.
♪ There's a devil inside of me
♪ He's holding on... ♪
Bastards!
♪ And I don't know if he's staying
or for how long
♪ There's a devil inside of me
♪ And he's holding on
♪ And I don't know if he's staying
or for how long... ♪
Party is it, eh? Is that what it is?
What's this, a party, eh?
Fuck off out of it!
Get out!
OK, I wasn't going to hit ya...
but that wasn't fucking nice.
Oh, you...
Arthur! Mr Shelby!
Please, Mr Shelby! Please.
Don't fucking move.
Eh? Eh? Now get the fuck out!
Fuck you and fuck your revolution!
I'm a fucking mess.
Where are you going?
Come here.
Fucking hit man, are you?
Is that what you are?
Arthur Shelby, hey!
Let's see who wanted you.
What about...
What about fucking John Shelby?
John.
Thank you.
Send my guests in.
You wire Polo and let him
tell the family.
He has four kids.
Don't you two have any other
clothes to wear?
Uh?
Look at me.
Huh?
I'm here as a lover of theatre.
They kill two of our men...
..you complain about
your fucking belly.
Luca.
Luca, con tutto rispetto...
With respect... "With respect?"
You raised.
"With respect?"
Open your mouth.
Come on...
Open your fucking mouth!
You fucking dress like them.
You eat like them.
You don't fucking talk to me
about "with respect".
Sit down.
What do you have?
Arthur Shelby killed her
son in a boxing ring four years ago.
She would do that for us?
OK.
Anyone seen Arthur?
Anyone seen Arthur? Hey?
In your office, Tom.
If you're not going to show up
for a family meeting,
you let someone know.
We thought you were dead,
there's 15 fucking
Italians out there.
No, there's not, there's 13.
I just killed two of them.
Ripped out their hearts
and burnt their bones to ash.
I did it.
Me. Your brother.
Not fucking Aberama Gold
or his punch-drunk son.
But me!
Even if you don't trust me no more.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Arthur?
I got cleaned up at Ada's.
She told me,
you took a vote in my absence.
All right, calm down and
tell me about the men you killed.
You put my job out for contract.
Arthur...
Yeah, well, I'm going to make it
my fucking job anyway.
Because this was all my fault.
It was me that shot the old man...
Yeah, out of mercy.
Aye, now John's dead,
he's dead because of me,
and I want to make it right.
Arthur, wait.
How did the men get in the factory?
I need to know.
Through the back fucking door
that was supposed to be locked
and bolted.
Some bastard gave me up.
Somebody with keys.
Yeah. Why don't you sit there
and work it out for yourself?
And take a fucking vote.
Who is this little bear? Yes?
Eh?
Are you all right?
Daddy's home, Billy.
Yeah, I'm all right.
Look, Daddy's home.
How's Polly?
Is she all right?
Oh, go on, Linda.
I mean, it was her idea, wasn't it?
Hum? The Japanese silk?
I'll put him to bed.
You kept me away
from that fucking meeting
to stop me from voting. Here we go.
It was Polly's idea, wasn't it?
Eh?
You know what I am, don't ya?
I am a working man.
Yeah.
Fucking working man.
Fucking... who's lost his job.
Is that what I am, Linda?
Is that what I am, eh?
I don't want you dead.
Polly doesn't want you dead.
Let Mr Gold do the killing.
For money.
It's the modern way, Arthur.
Watch.
What are you doing?
Now fire it into the fireplace.
Please.
All right. Fire it.
Get rid of it.
Then we'll go to bed.
Do anything you like.
Just fire the gun, Arthur.
Fire it.
You go tell Polly...
..there are rules
between a man and women.
Fucking rules.
That I have to do this.
I have to do it.
John wants me to do it, Linda.
My brother.
And I'm going to do it.
Was it fear, or was it hatred?
Was what fear or hatred? Isaiah...
You had a one way ticket
to Glasgow in your pocket.
Your wife and kids
left three days ago.
Now... I'm going to ask you again.
Was it fear of the Italians,
or hatred of us
that made you unlock the door
and give up my brother?
I didn't unlock any door.
Here, have a drink.
You're going to need it.
35 Drumcree Street,
Parkhead, Glasgow...
Please, please, please, please...
We have allegiances with Catholic
gangs in that city.
Your family are safe
only at my discretion.
Now... explain to me...
..why you were catching
a midnight train to Glasgow.
You mean you don't know?
I run a factory full of blackleg,
non-union labour.
I live in a street full of men
laid off or on strike.
Look at this photograph, Mr Devlin,
and tell me who are the men
who contacted you... No.
No, you listen to me.
I get spat at,
windows smashed,
petrol on the curtains...
..but, for fear of you,
I clock in every fucking morning -
and, today, two men are shot
and burnt on my shift...
..and you ask me why I'm getting
the midnight train to Glasgow?
Who else has the keys to that door?
They hang on a hook
inside my office.
Today, I left the office unlocked.
Why? Because I forgot.
Because I left in a hurry.
Because there were men trying
to set fire to the factory!
Mr Shelby, may I tell you something?
You have a lot of enemies.
Communists.
Italians.
Before the factory came out
on strike,
I heard word that two Italians
attended a Communist Party meeting
in Stechford.
They hardly spoke English.
Now, if they got a party man
into the factory
it might have been him
that unlocked the door for them.
Mr Shelby... my train leaves at 12.
It's just gone 11.
I could still make it.
Please. For my kids.
I need you here.
Isaiah, get three of our men
with police badges
to watch Mr Devlin's house.
Mr Shelby, please...
Our friends in Glasgow
will take care of your family.
For the curtains.
Before you, I was
an ordinary working man.
Yeah, and now you're one of us.
Bye Bye Blackbird
by Gene Austin
♪ Blackbird, blackbird
♪ Singing the blues all day
♪ Right outside of my door... ♪
Who is it?
It's Tommy Shelby.
Is this union business?
Yes.
So, conduct it in the proper
place at the proper time.
I've come to make an improved offer.
I heard music.
What's your improved offer?
Do I not get a drink?
No.
Have you ever seen any of the men
in this photograph before?
You're a member
of the Stechford Communist party.
I'm told two Italian men
attended a meeting recently.
Can you see either of them
in this picture?
As the Small Heath coordinator
of the Organisation for the
Maintenance of Supplies,
I have also
been sworn in as a Special...
We have reason to believe
that outside agitators from overseas
are attempting to foment
trouble in our factories
in advance of a General Strike,
which could take place
at any moment.
This is a matter
of national security.
May I look at your badge?
Yes.
What would you like to drink,
Constable?
Whisky.
And, actually, it's Sergeant.
I only have beer. Times are hard.
How long has it been since
you've had a bottle of M&B bitter?
Help yourself.
Have a seat.
You know, when this business began,
I did some research on you.
It turns out I know someone
who used to know you very well.
Kitty Jurossi.
You were in love with
Kitty's sister, Greta Jurossi,
before the war.
Do you remember Greta Jurossi?
Her parents were Italian.
They didn't approve
of a Watery Lane Gypsy...
..but you won them over.
With your charm.
Sweetness.
Very... Very thorough research.
Greta died at the age of 19.
Of consumption...
..and Kitty said you were
at her bedside for three months.
Every day. Holding her hand...
..and after she died,
you went away to war.
Kitty said that the sweet boy
who left never came back.
No-one came back.
Here's the funniest thing.
She said, in those days,
you believed in things.
In justice. Fairness.
Once you saw a man beating
his horse, and you fought him.
He was twice your size,
but you beat him...
..and then you beat him
with his own whip.
Kitty always liked
to tell tall tales.
She's a party member now.
She swears before you enlisted
in the army
you joined the
Communist Party yourself.
Is that true?
When I was at the door,
I saw you through the curtains.
You were dancing alone.
I've also done my research.
Your sweetheart
was at Passchendaele.
When he came back, he was
listed among the shellshocked.
Blew his own fucking brains out.
I don't know any men in the photo.
You haven't looked.
This afternoon,
two men came into my factory
and tried to kill my brother.
I believe a Stechford
Communist Party member let him in.
I was wondering if you might be able
to help me in my investigations.
Kitty said next time I see you,
before we start fighting,
I should send you her love
from the good old days...
..and give you this.
Greta Jurossi and Tommy Shelby
in Blackpool.
Do you recognise
the boy in the photograph?
I'll leave that here.
Apologies for interrupting
your dance.
♪ I wish
♪ But it's all in vain
♪ I wish I was
♪ A maid again
♪ But a maid again
♪ I never can be
♪ Till apples grow... ♪
Arthur, I need you to listen to me.
I need you to listen to me,
Arthur.
The world is changing.
Listen to me, Arthur.
Listen to the sweet
voice of Jesus.
Finn? It came from Arthur's house.
Arthur.
Where is he?
Arthur?
He fired the bullet.
Linda...
..says it's the modern way, so...
It's the modern way.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, it's all right.
It's all right, brother.
You did well.
God spoke to him, not me.
What are you doing here?
On Mondays, I do the inventory.
Make sure nobody's
dipping their hand.
Well, it's now my job now.
I'm back -
and there's going to be nobody
dipping their hand with me here,
not unless they want it cut off.
I said to Arthur,
while I'm in this fucking place,
I want something to keep
my mind busy.
What? You're going to take bets?
I've always been able to do addition
and subtraction
without pen and paper -
but I'll need a telephone.
Apparently, we have special clients
who take bets by telephone.
Linda?
This is a betting shop.
Look...
..Arthur said yes. Tommy said yes.
But did God say yes?
Gambling is a sin, Linda.
It's not me
that's doing the gambling.
I'm just taking the bets.
The rule is that door should
always remain locked until 9am.
Right. Boy.
Boy, where are you going?
Well, Arthur's not coming in today.
He's taking the day off.
So... So what?
So, today,
Tommy said that I'm in charge.
Sorry, you're in charge?
Yeah. That's what he said.
All right, sweetheart.
Ladies, let's give our boss a first
day that he'll never forget.
Sending Finn to the shop
was a mistake.
They've already found out he's a
virgin and they're arranging
a girl for him this afternoon.
I thought Linda was there.
She is. She loved the idea.
Yeah, I know. She even swears now.
"Fuck" sounds funny coming from her.
Polly says in the end
we all turn into our mother.
Ah, well, keep an eye on her.
The whore watching the Madonna.
Does Finn know what
they've planned? No.
Do they have someone?
Yes. A girl I used to work with.
Is she nice? No. She's from Aston.
They're paying her
out of petty cash.
Right, well, call 'em and tell them
to pay extra and get someone nice.
Nice women don't do that sort of
thing. Yes, they do. What a
I mean, in the past. Come on.
Where are we going?
Somewhere I've not
been in a long time.
Are we expecting somebody?
Tommy, I'm fucking freezing here.
We used to come here.
She'd wait for hours for me,
when I couldn't make it...
..and I'd wait for her,
if her family kept her in.
Who?
Some girl.
Some girl before France.
I've not been back here since...
..but I wanted to come here
with you.
Are you kissing her or me?
You.
I want Shelby Company Limited
to increase non-taxable charitable
contributions to local charities
by 25% as of now...
..and I'm going to build two new
institutes for destitute children.
One in Saltley, one in Digbeth.
I've already identified
the buildings.
Two former workhouses.
I want you to be
in charge of the project.
Right, come on, let's go.
Why?
Because I promised someone
I was going to change the world.
You do realise, Tommy,
we're all going fucking mad here.
Yeah, I know. Come on.
Finn? Come here.
How was your day?
Yeah, it was OK.
Good man. Well done.
No trouble?
No. No trouble.
And she looked after you?
I don't want it like that
ever again, Tom.
Not when they don't even want to
do it, except for the money.
Everything's for the money, Finn.
Yeah, I know. But, er...
She said "be a man".
And were you a man?
Yeah...
..but then I apologised to her,
cos she just looked so tired.
Sit down, Finn.
Right, listen to me, Finn.
She was right.
You need to be a fucking man.
People get tired.
Working in a fucking factory
gets you tired.
I don't go round apologising. Do I?
No.
There's an empty space here
to be filled.
Do you understand? Yeah.
So, be a fucking man.
OK, Tom.
Champagne, please. Of course.
Madam, women alone
are not allowed at the bar.
Will someone be joining you?
What do you think?
This is public enough, no?
Yes.
So?
The boy in the hospital
is out of bounds...
..and I'll ask you to spare
Finn and Arthur.
In return for what?
Tommy Shelby.
And, er, why should I trust you?
Because you know our history.
You know what happened between us.
You are an unlikely Cassius.
You know, my mother...
My mother knew your mother.
She taught her how to read.
Did she tell you that John
and Arthur spared her life?
When Tommy wanted her dead.
Yeah - and now she's giving me
the information about you people.
So, Tommy Shelby was right.
His ruthlessness... was justified.
You should have killed her
when you had the chance.
John was a good boy.
Arthur tries.
Tommy's different.
You take Tommy. Spare the rest.
You know, my mother used
to say this about you.
She said, "That Polly Gray,
"that child would never let
go of a grievance...
"..and she loves to dance."
What do you say, hm?
You want to dance?
I don't dance any more.
Yeah, that's a shame...
..cos you're dancing with me.